Guide to the Carol D. Litchfield microbiology collection, 1924-1997
George Mason University Libraries
- Carol D. Litchfield Microbiology collection, 1924-1997
  - NOAA Magazine, October 1976 (Box 10, Volume 5)
    Volume 6 Number 4
  - National Geographic Magazine, March 1985 (Box 10, Volume 6)
    National Geographic
    Vol.167, No.3
  - Maritimes, May 1983 (Box 10, Volume 7)
    University of Rhode Island Graduate School of Oceanography.
    Volume 27 Number 2
  - World Ocean Floors Pacific Ocean, June 1992 (Box 10, Volume 8)
    Map
  - Estuarine and Coastal Marine Science., 1973 (Box 10, Volume 9)
    Academic Press London and New York
    Volume 1, Contents and Index
  - Estuarine and Coastal Marine Science., 1974 (Box 10, Volume 10)
    Volume 2, Contents and Index
  - Estuarine and Coastal Marine Science., 1975 (Box 10, Volume 11)
    Volume 3, Contents and Index
  - Abdruck aus Centralblatt fur Bakteriologie, Parasitenkunde und Infektionskrankheiten, 1928 (Box 10, Volume 12)
    Prof. Dr. F. Lohnis und Reg.-Rat Prof. Dr. K. Friederichs
    Band 75 (Volume 75)
  - No Sea Too Deep The History of Oceanographic Instruments, 1982 (Box 10, Volume 13)
    Anita McConnell
    Curator of the Oceanography Collection Science Museum, London
  - Biological Analysis of Water and Wastewater, 1973 (Box 10, Volume 14)
    Application Manual AM302
  - Jamaica Bay Environmental Conference Cosystem Revitalization 1984 (Box 10, Volume 15)
    Sponsored by: Congressman Joseph P. Addabbo with Congressman Charles E. Schumer, NYC Chapter Sierra Club, NYC Citizens Advisory Committee, and Gateway National Recreation Area
  - Nitrogen Cycle, September 1970 (Box 10, Volume 16)
    C.C. Delwiche
    Scientific American Offprints Vol.223,No.3 PP.136-146
  - The Oxygen Cycle, September 1970 (Box 10, Volume 17)
    Preston Cloud and Aharon Gibor
    Scientific American Offprints Vol.223, No.3 PP.110-123
  - Seaport, Fall 1978 (Box 10, Volume 18)
    Seaport The Magazine of South Street Seaport Museum
    Volume XII Number 3
  - ASTM Standardization News, October 1979 (Box 10, Volume 19)
    Volume 7, Number 10
  - Oceans Magazine, 1977 (Box 10, Volume 20)
    A publication of the Oceanic Society
    Number 6, 1977
  - American Scientist, July-August 1992 (Box 10, Volume 21)
    Published by Sigma Xi, magazine
    Volume 80, Number 4
  - American Scientist, September-October 1972 (Box 10, Volume 22)
    American Scientist magazine
    Volume 60 Number 5
  - Scientific American, September 1983 (Box 10, Volume 23)
    Scientific American magazine
    Volume 249 Number 3
  - 1969-1970 Progress Report Duke University Cooperative Research and Training Program in Biological Oceanography (Box 10, Volume 24)
    Dr. C.G. Bookhout, Dr. Richard T. Barber, Mr. John G. Newton
    Progress Report
  - 1972-73 Progress Report Duke University Cooperative Oceanographic Program, 1973 (Box 10, Volume 25)
    Dr. Richard T. Barber and Mr. John G. Newton
  - 1973-74 Progress Report Duke University Cooperative Oceanographic Program, 1974 (Box 10, Volume 26)
  - Publications Resulting from Research Aboard R/V Eastward, 1973 (Box 10, Volume 27)
    Duke University Marine Laboratory
    R/V Eastward Cruises 1964-1973
  - Manual for Use of R/V Eastward, September 1968 (Box 10, Volume 28)
    Duke University Cooperative Research and Training Program in Biological Oceanography
  - Coastal Water Research Project, 1978 (Box 10, Volume 29)
    Southern California Coastal Water Research Project, Edited by: Willard Bascom
    Annual Report
  - Coastal Water Research Project., 1981-1982 (Box 10, Volume 29)
    Southern California Coastal Water Reseach Project, Edited by: Willard Bascom
    Biennial Report
  - Rapport D'Activite [Activity Report], 1970 (Box 10, Volume 30)
    Centre D'etudes et de Recheres de Biologie et D'Oceanographie Medicale (C.E.R.B.O.M.)
    Institut National de la Sante et de la Recherche Medicale, Nice
  - Rapport D'Activite [Activity Report], 1971 (Box 10, Volume 31)
  - Summary Report for Fiscal Years 1979 and 1980, July 1982 (Box 10, Volume 32)
    Office of Marine Pollution Assessment Northeast Office
    Summary report
  - National Oceanographic Data Center Annual Report 1982, July 1983 (Box 10, Volume 33)
    DOC
  - Annual NEMP Report of the Health of the Northeast Coastal Waters of the United States, 1981, February 1983 (Box 10, Volume 34)
    DOC, NOAA
    NOAA Technical Memorandum NMFS-F/NEC-20
  - The Japan Sea: A Literature Review, December 1987 (Box 10, Volume 35)
    Barbara Jacobs Dinkins
    For E.I. du Pont de Nemours and Company
  - Final Report of Beneficial Stimulations of Bacterial Activity in Ground Waters Containing Petroleum Products., Marcy 1975 (Box 10, Volume 36)
    R.L. Raymond, V.W. Jamison, and J.O. Hudson
  - Oil Spill Response Bioremediation Agents., July 1993 (Box 10, Volume 37)
    National Environmental Technology Applications Center
    Evaluation Methods Manual; contains a letter to Dr. Litchfield
  - The Effect of Bioremediation on the Oil Spill of the Exxon Valdez in Alaska, Fall 1994 (Box 10, Volume 38)
    Terry R. Creque
    Presentation slides and script
  - LIA Meeting California Regional Water Quality Board, January 1990 (Box 10, Volume 39)
    Du Pont Environmental Services; C.H. Ward, J.M. Thomas, S. Fiorenza, H.S. Rifai, P.B. Bedient, J.M. Armstrong, J.T. Wilscon, and R.L. Raymond, M.D. Lee
    Meeting proceedings (Raymond and Others Ref.)
  - Field Application of Subsurface Biodegradation of Gasoline in a Sand Formation, August 1978 (Box 10, Volume 40)
    Work by: R.L. Raymond, V.W. Jamison, J.O. Hudson, and R.E. Mitchell, and V.E. Farmer
    Final Report Project No. 307-77 API
  - In Situ Bioremediation of Spills from Underground Storage Tanks: New Approaches for Site Characterization, Project Design, and Evaluation of Performance., July 1989 (Box 10, Volume 41)
    John T. Wilson, Lowell E. Leach, Joseph Michalowski, Steve Vandegrift, and Randy Callaway
  - Column Flow Studies of Bioremediation in Prince William Sound, April 1990 (Box 10, Volume 42)
    James R. Bragg, John C. Roffall, Sara McMillen
  - Treatment Technology for Removal of Dissolved Gasoline Components from Ground Water, May 1983 (Box 10, Volume 43)
    Prepared by: IT Enviroscience, Knoxville, TN
  - Treatment Technology for Removal of Dissolved Gasoline Components from Ground Water, May 1983 (Box 10, Volume 44)
    Final Report Volume 2
  - Texas Plans -- A Checklist and Ecological Summary, June 1962 (Box 10, Volume 45)
    F.W. Gould
    Reference
  - Operation Sail 1976 (Box 10, Volume 46)
    Operation Sail
  - Laboratory Scale Gasoline Spill and Venting Experiment, October 1980 (Box 11, Volume 1)
    Texas Research Institute, Inc.
    Interim Report
  - Groundwater Abatement Techniques for Removal of Refined Hydrocarbons, March 1983 (Box 11, Volume 2)
    Prepared by: Paul M. Yaniga
    National Conference on Hazardous Wastes and Environmental Emergencies
  - A Study of Disease Incidence and Recreational Water Quality in the Great Lakes Phase 1, September 1980 (Box 11, Volume 3)
    Environmental Health Direcorate Health Protection Branch
    Study
  - Human Viruses in the Aquatic Environment: A Status Report With Emphasis on the EPA Research Program, December 1978 (Box 11, Volume 4)
    Environmental Research Center
    Report to Congress
  - An Environmental Assessment of Wetlands" A Case Study of Woodbury Creek and Associated Marshes, September 1975 (Box 11, Volume 5)
    Ralph E. Good, Robert W. Hastings, Roy E. Denmark
    Technical Report No. 75-2
  - Health Effects of Nitrates in Water, June 1977 (Box 11, Volume 6)
    Hillel I. Shuval, Nachman Gruener
    EPA-600/1-77-030
  - Raritan Bay Its Multiple Uses and Abuses, 1983 (Box 11, Volume 7)
    Anthony L. Pacheco
    Proceedings of the Walford Memorial Convocation
  - Synoptic Investigation of Nutrient Cycling in the Coastal Plume of the Hudson and Raritan Rivers: Plankton Dynamics, August 1982 (Box 11, Volume 8)
    Thomas C. Malone, Mira B. Chervin, C. Garside, Carol D. Litchfield, Jeanne C. Stepien, and J.P. Thomas
    Attached is a letter to Dr. Garry F. Mayer from Thomas C. More
  - Distribution of the Standing Crop of Total Net Plankton Off the Texas Coast, September 1955 (Box 11, Volume 9)
    Kenneth H. Drummond and Jerome E. Stein
    AandM Project 77 - Reference 55-30T
  - The Role of Ecology in the Federal Government, December 1974 (Box 11, Volume 10)
    Russel W. Peterson and H. Guyford Stever
    Report of the Committee on Ecological Research
  - Coastal Resource and Development Policies, April 1982 (Box 11, Volume 11)
    Prepared by: State of New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection Division of Coastal Resources Bureau of Coastal Planning and Development
    Policies handbook
  - Sewage Effects in Marine and Estuarine Environments, May 1975 (Box 11, Volume 12)
    Edward J. Lehmann
    A Bibliography with Abstracts
  - Assessment of Alternatives for Beach Nourishment: at Southern Recreation Beaches, Sandy Hook Unit, Gateway National Recreation Area, November 1977 (Box 11, Volume 13)
    Douglas J. Sherman, Joseph J. Andrea, Allan B. Campbell, Paul A. Gares, Gail A. Kucma, Chizuko Mizobe, David W. Morris, Karl F. Nordstrom, Norbert P. Psuty, Gary A. Rojek
    Report for the North Atlantic Regional Office of the National Park Service
  - Nutrient Exchange in Water-Sediment Interface and Its Effects on Water Quality, 1975 (Box 11, Volume 14)
    Calvin P. C. Poon
    Project Completion Report
  - Physical Properties and Suspended Matter of Surface Waters in the Southeastern Atlantic Ocean, January 1973 (Box 11, Volume 15)
    K.O. Emery, J.D. Milliman, and Elazar Uchupi
    Technical Report
  - A Characterization of the Lipids of the Organisms Which Make Up the Main Bulk of a Coral Reef with Particular Emphasis on the Hydrocarbons, January 1965 (Box 11, Volume 16)
    Texas AandM Research Foundation
  - Technical and Philosophical Aspects of Ocean Disposal, November 1977 (Box 11, Volume 17)
    marchi C. Zapatka and Roy W.Hann, Jr.
  - Environment Benchmark Studies in Casco Bay - Portland Harbor, Maine, April 1980, January 1983 (Box 11, Volume 18)
    Peter F. Larsen, Anne C. Johnson, and Lee F. Doggett
    NOAA Technical Memorandum NMFS-F/NEC-19
  - Chesapeake Bay Plume Study Superflux 1980, January 1981 (Box 11, Volume 19)
    Edited by: Janet W. Campbell and James P. Thomas
    Proceeding of a Symposium held in Williamsburg, VA; NASA Conference Publication 2188 NOAA/NEMP III 81 ABCDFG 0042
  - Environmental Factors in Coastal and Estarine Waters Bibliographic Series-Volume II Coast of Washington, August 1968 (Box 11, Volume 20)
    George R. Ditsworth
  - Cadmium Pollution Volume 1. 1964 - November 1977, October 1978 (Box 11, Volume 21)
    Mona F. Smith
  - Sewage Effects in Marine and Estuarine Environments. Volume 1. 1964 - 1976, June 1978 (Box 11, Volume 22)
    Robena J. Brown
  - Sewage Effects in Marine and Estuarine Environments. Volume 2. 1977 - May 1978, June 1978 (Box 11, Volume 23)
  - Quality Assurance/Quality Control in Waste Site Characterization and Remedial Action, Time covered: December 1986 - June 1987 (Box 11, Volume 24)
    M.P. Maskarinec and S.K. Holladay
    Government Reports from Information On Demand, Report No. AD-A188539, Final Report
  - Ground Water Volume I: Ground Water and Contamination, September 1990 (Box 11, Volume 25)
    Authors and Reviewers: Michael J. Barcelona, Russell Boulding, Ralph C. Heath, Jack Keely, Wayne A. Pettyjohn
    Handbook
  - Ground Water Volume II: Methodology., July 1991 (Box 11, Volume 26)
    Authors and Reviewers: Michael J. Barcelona, Russell Boulding, Ralph C. Heath, Wayne A. Pettyjohn, Ron Sims, Judy Sims, Paul van der Heijde, H. Allen Wehrman
  - Natural and Accelerated Bioremediation Research NABIR Program Plan, September 1995 (Box 11, Volume 27)
    Michelle S. Broido, Acting Director
    Program Plan, DOE/ER-0659T
  - Technical Support Document for Water Quality-based Control, July 1985 (Box 11, Volume 28)
    James M. Conlon and Rebecca W. Hamner
    Technical Support Document
  - Retrospective Epidemiological Study of Disease Associated with Wastewater Utilization, May 1984 (Box 11, Volume 29)
    Hillel I. Shuval, Badri Fattal, and Yochanan Wax
  - Review of 37 Office of Drinking Water Health Advisories, October 1986 (Box 11, Volume 30)
    Environmental Health Committee
  - Ambient Water Quality Criteria for Tricholroethylene, October 1980 (Box 11, Volume 31)
    Environmental Criteria and Assessment Office
    EPA 440/5-80-077
  - Elevation of the Acute Toxicity of Selected Groundwater Contaminants, April 1987 (Box 11, Volume 32)
    Edwin R. Kinkead and Harold F. Leahy
    Government Reports from Information On Demand Report No. AD-A180198
  - Methods for Microbiological Analysis of Waters, Wastewaters and Sediments, 1978 (Box 11, Volume 33)
    B.J. Dutka
    Methodology
  - Wastes Management Concepts for the Coastal Zone Requirements for Research and Investigation., 1970 (Box 11, Volume 34)
    Committee on Oceanography and Committee on Ocean Engineering
  - Report on a Colloquium Sponsored by the Water Science and Technology Board, May 1986 (Box 11, Volume 35)
    National Water Quality Monitoring and Assessment
    Colloquium 2 of a Series
  - Ocean Development and International Law, 1988 (Box 11, Volume 36)
    Richard J. McLaughlin, Jill L. Bubier, David W. Fischer, Christopher C. Joyner
    Volume 19 Number 1
  - Limu An Ethnobotanical Study of Some Edible Hawaiian Seaweeds, 1974 (Box 11, Volume 37)
    Isabella Aiona Abbott and Eleanor Horswill Williamson
    Study/Guide
  - Heavy Metals in Wastewater and Treatment Plant Effluents., September 1973 (Box 11, Volume 38)
    Alan I. Mytelka, Joseph S. Czachor, William Guggino, and Howard Golub
    Journal Water Pollution Control Federation
  - Morphometric Features and the Classification of all the Lakes in Japan, 1962 (Box 11, Volume 39)
    Shoji Horie
    Reprinted from the Memoirs of the College of Science, University of Kyoto, Series B, Vol. XXIX, No.3